export const cryptoTaxGlossary: {
    [key: string]: {
        question: string;
        answer: string;
    }[]
}[] = [
        {
            "A": [
                {
                    question: "Accounting Period",
                    answer: "This is a period of one year or 12 Months. For Individuals, it ranges from January to December and for companies, it follows the normal accounting dates for preparation of accounts."
                },
                {
                    question: "Airdrops",
                    answer: "An airdrop is a distribution of a cryptocurrency token or coin, usually for free, to numerous wallet addresses. Airdrops are primarily implemented as a way of gaining attention and new followers, resulting in a larger user-base and a wider disbursement of coins."
                },
                {
                    question: "Average Cost Method",
                    answer: "This method of calculating taxable income recalculates unit cost of cryptocurrency at every point of purchase. Therefore, where a disposal occurs, the cost of the disposed asset is calculated using the average cost of all the acquired assets in the wallet."
                }
            ],

            "B": [
                {
                    question: "Blockchain",
                    answer: "A blockchain acts as a database, storing information in a decentralized platform. It can be accessed across computer network nodes. They are well known for their critical function in keeping a secure and decentralized record of transactions in cryptocurrency systems like Bitcoin. The most popular application of blockchain is cryptocurrency. Unlike currency, crypto employs blockchain to operate as a public ledger and an advanced cryptographic security system, ensuring that all online transactions are processed and safeguarded."
                },
            ],

            "C": [
                {
                    question: "Crypto as a gift",
                    answer: "This is crypto that is transferred from another wallet which is not as a result of a purchase transaction but sent as a gift."
                },
                {
                    question: "Crypto Miscellaneous Income",
                    answer: "If you earn money from mining or staking crypto, crypto rewards, promotional incentives from a crypto broker or exchange, or related crypto activity, the IRS considers this miscellaneous income."
                },
                {
                    question: "Cryptocurrency fees",
                    answer: "These are fees charged for transactions from buying, selling, transfers, trading, etc. These fees are allowed for tax purposes, to be deductible on disposition of assets and are to be added on cost basis on the acquisition of crypto."
                },
                {
                    question: "Cryptocurrency Gain",
                    answer: "The gain or excess of the value at which crypto is bought and the value at which it is sold, within an accounting period. This gain is subject to Personal Income Tax for Individuals and Company Income Tax for entities."
                },
                {
                    question: "Cryptocurrency Loss",
                    answer: "The loss or value reduction in the value at which crypto is bought and the value at which it is sold within an accounting period. There should be a limit to which the loss can be carried forward both in value and in years. This loss can be carried forward and deducted from the subsequent years gains before charging tax."
                },
                {
                    question: "Carryforward",
                    answer: "Using tax losses from prior years to offset capital gains from the current tax year"
                },
                {
                    question: "Cryptocurrency Capital gains",
                    answer: "Earnings made from the appreciation and subsequent sale or trade of an asset"
                },
                {
                    question: "Centralized exchange (CEX)",
                    answer: "An organization that brokers sales and trades of tokens and is owned and governed by a known entity or entities. These must typically follow know-your-customer (KYC) rules and report to tax authorities. Examples: Coinbase, Gemini, Binance"
                },
                {
                    question: "Cost Basis",
                    answer: "The amount a trader paid for an asset, plus additions for any applicable fees"
                },
                {
                    question: "Cryptocurrency",
                    answer: "A cryptocurrency is a digital currency (also called virtual currency) that is protected by encryption, making counterfeiting and double-spending exceedingly difficult. It is monitored and verified by blockchain (a decentralized peer-to-peer network). Cryptocurrencies are mined or bought on cryptocurrency exchanges. Not all e-commerce sites accept cryptocurrency payments. Nevertheless, cryptocurrencies' expected potential has made them prominent as trading instruments. They are also utilized for cross-border transactions to a limited degree."
                }
            ],

            "D": [
                {
                    question: "Deductions",
                    answer: "These are purchases or expenses you can use to offset your annual taxable income. Crypto losses on selling, converting, or other dispositions are considered deductions, and you can offset your capital gains. If your losses exceed your capital gains in a given tax year, you can offset it against ordinary income but with a limit cap and carry forward any excess losses as deductions in future tax years (this is known as a tax loss carryforward)."
                },
                {
                    question: "Decentralized autonomous organization (DAO)",
                    answer: "An organization (social or commercial) governed by rules encoded in smart contracts stored on the blockchain rather than by any centralized leadership. Examples: Uniswap, MakerDAO, FWB, Radicle."
                },
                {
                    question: "Decentralized finance (DeFi)",
                    answer: "A broad umbrella term for financial instruments (exchanges, brokerages, etc) made directly accessible to investors via smart contracts on a blockchain. DeFi aims to increase access to investment opportunities by bypassing traditional third-party intermediaries."
                },
                {
                    question: "Disposal",
                    answer: "Accounting term for relinquishing control over an asset through a sale, swap, trade, or some other mechanism."
                }
            ],

            "E": [
                {
                    question: "Earning Programs",
                    answer: "This has to do with rewards earned for performing some activities. For example, watch videos or read articles, then take quizzes, and if you pass, as an incentive, you will earn a specified amount of crypto assets as a reward. Another example is earning from a blockchain game. You — as a crypto user — are going to learn new concepts and earn some."
                },
                {
                    question: "Estimated Taxes",
                    answer: "A payment of a portion of your expected total tax liability, these are due four times a year from people who expect to make significant amount of income through self-employment."
                }
            ],

            "F": [
                {
                    question: "First In First Out Method",
                    answer: "This method is a taxation method in which assets (cryptocurrencies) acquired first are disposed of first. That is, whenever a sale of an acquired asset occurs, it is assumed that the asset being sold is the first that was acquired."
                },
                {
                    question: "Fiat",
                    answer: "Government-issued currency not backed by any commodity. Examples: USD, CAD, EUR, JPY."
                }
            ],

            "G": [
                {
                    question: "Gas fee",
                    answer: "A transaction fee paid to a blockchain network anytime a transaction takes place. Gas fees can sometimes be added to an asset’s cost basis."
                }
            ],

            "H": [
                {
                    question: "Hard fork",
                    answer: "In the past, there have been a few high-profile hard forks, like when Bitcoin Cash was created in 2017. In this case, anyone who owned Bitcoin on the network at the time was able to receive an equal amount of Bitcoin Cash after a new, separate blockchain was created from the original. In a 2021 memorandum, the IRS clarifies that any earnings received from a hard fork are indeed treated as income."
                },
                {
                    question: "Holding period",
                    answer: "The amount of time an investor keeps an asset after acquiring it and before trading or selling it."
                }
            ],

            "I": [
                {
                    question: "Inheritance",
                    answer: "This is cryptocurrency received as an inheritance as a result of close relation to a deceased person."
                },
                {
                    question: "Internal Revenue Service",
                    answer: "The Internal Revenue Service (IRS) is the federal government agency responsible for administering and enforcing tax laws, which includes the collection of taxes."
                }
            ],

            "L": [
                {
                    question: "Last In First Out Method",
                    answer: "This method is a taxation method in which the last assets (cryptocurrencies) acquired are disposed of first. That is, whenever a sale of acquired assets occurs, it is assumed that the asset being sold is the last or most recently acquired."
                },
                {
                    question: "Long-term gain",
                    answer: "A long-term gain (or loss) is one realized when the sold capital asset’s holding period was one year or more. Long-term gains receive preferable tax treatment for individual taxpayers."
                },
                {
                    question: "Loss harvesting",
                    answer: "Tax-loss harvesting means selling crypto when its value drops below the amount you paid for it. These losses can be used to offset any capital gains you realized in the same year. And if you haven’t realized capital gains from selling crypto, you can offset ordinary income with a limit cap when you file income taxes. It’s important to note that losses have to be used to offset capital gains first. And when you’re using capital losses to offset capital gains, you have to offset gains of the same type first: Long-term losses offset long-term gains; Short-term losses offset short-term gains."
                },
            ],

            "M": [
                {
                    question: "Margin Trading",
                    answer: "Margin trading is leveraging your assets in order to have greater market exposure. Exchanges that allow margin will essentially make you a loan with your cryptocurrency as collateral in order to have the potential for greater returns. Trading cryptocurrency on margin can carry greater risks, but have the potential for greater returns."
                },
                {
                    question: "Mining Income",
                    answer: "This is the fair market value of crypto (as of the date of receipt) received as a reward for successfully mining a transaction."
                }
            ]
        }
    ]